José Antonio Azócar Marcano

Location: San Diego, Carabobo - Venezuela

Email: azocarone@gmail.com Phone: +584144158626 Website: azocar.one

Professional Summary

Computer Science Engineer with a Master's degree in E-commerce, specializing in consulting and the development of technological solutions. Has extensive experience in system management, cybersecurity, and the development of innovative projects. Excels in implementing advanced technologies and optimizing processes. Technical skills in programming and web development, along with strong interpersonal skills that enable leading teams toward the achievement of common goals.

Work Experience

IT Advisor

January 2010 – Present Self-Employed Valencia, Venezuela

- Manage and maintain servers and workstations based on GNU/Linux operating systems
- Design and administer LAN networks
- Implement cybersecurity measures and perform forensic analysis
- Develop technological projects using platforms such as Arduino and Raspberry Pi
- Develop technological projects using platforms such as Arduino and Raspberry Pi
- Implement and optimize web hosting services
- Resolve computer incidents efficiently
- Perform specialized electrical installations

Systems Coordinator

May 2007 – October 2009 Almacenes y Depósitos Integrales Portuarios, C.A. Puerto Cabello, Venezuela

- Comply with customs regulations for import and export operations
- Increase the efficiency of logistics personnel
- Optimize inventory accuracy
- Plan operational resources
- Reduce ship loading and unloading times
- Ensure the physical security of the cargo
- Carry out dispatches in a timely manner

Master's Intern in E-commerce

March 2006 – July 2006 CompuMarket S.A. Madrid, Spain

- Acquire knowledge in analysis and management of online sales
- Master SEO techniques
- Manage web content
- Analyze online competition
- Implement Internet marketing strategies
- Meet quality and efficiency standards,

Academic Education

- Máster en Comercio Electrónico, Universidad "Carlos III de Madrid", Madrid, España, October 2005 September 2006
- Ingeniería en Informática, Universidad "Alejandro de Humboldt", <u>Caracas, Venezuela,</u> September 1999 June 2004
- Técnico Superior en Computación, Instituto Universitario de "Nuevas Profesiones", Valencia, Venezuela,
 September 1988 December 1992

Continuous Training

- Introducción a Machine Learning, Código Facilito, Tuxtla Gutiérrez, México, March 2024
- GitHub Copilot, Código Facilito, Tuxtla Gutiérrez, México, March 2024
- Profesional de Docker, Código Facilito, Tuxtla Gutiérrez, México, November 2023
- Pofesional de Python, Código Facilito, <u>Tuxtla Gutiérrez</u>, <u>México</u>, June 2023

Certifications

• Program Oracle Next Education, Alura Latam, São Paulo, Brasil, January 2023

Technical Skills

- GNU/Linux, Networking, Cybersecurity, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Docker,
- Raspberry Pi, Arduino, VS Code, GitHub, Trello, Discord, Forensic analysis, SEO,
- Fedora Linux

Soft Skills

- Quick adaptation to new situations, Task organization, Teamwork,
- Clear and effective communication, Leadership, Positive influence, Results-oriented focus,
- Resilience

Languages

• Native Spanish (C2), • Basic-Intermediate English (A1-A2)